Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Competitive Advertisements, Pre-55 Group, 1894-1957
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Competitive Advertisements, Pre-55 Group, 1894-1957
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company
108 linear feet Extent: About 75,000 Items
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. The collection spans the years 1894-1957 and includes newspaper and magazine print advertisements for companies which were competitors of JWT clients. Product categories include automobiles and transportation; bakeries and baked goods; beverages including alcoholic, carbonated, bottled water, coffee and soft drinks; cleaning products; cosmetics, shaving preparations and other toiletries; dairy products; food including pet foods; gasoline, oil and other petroleum products; newspapers and magazines; over-the-counter pharmaceuticals; and tobacco products including cigars, cigarettes and pipe tobacco. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
RL.00676
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is restricted.
Some materials are fragile and may require further processing prior to access. Contact Research Services staff for further information.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Competitive Advertisements, Pre-55 Group were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1987.
Collection Overview
The collection spans the years 1894-1957 and includes newspaper and magazine print advertisements for companies which were competitors of JWT clients. Product categories include automobiles and transportation; bakeries and baked goods; beverages including alcoholic, carbonated, bottled water, coffee and soft drinks; cleaning products; cosmetics, shaving preparations and other toiletries; dairy products; food including pet foods; gasoline, oil and other petroleum products; newspapers and magazines; over-the-counter pharmaceuticals; and tobacco products including cigars, cigarettes and pipe tobacco.
Subject Headings
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Preliminary Description of Collection
- Container List
  - Advertising industry
    - Joint Advertising, 1948 (Box 1)
    - Advertising agencies (Box 1)
    - N. W. Ayer & Son, 1948-1954, (7 folders) (Box 1)
    - Batton, Barton, Durstine & Osborn (BBDO), 1948-1954, (1-6 of 7 folders) (Box 1)
    - Batton, Barton, Durstine & Osborn (BBDO), 1951, (7 of 7 folders) (Box 2)
    - Cunningham & Walsh, 1954 (Box 2)
    - Charles W Hoyt, 1948-1953, (6 folders) (Box 2)
    - Lennen & Newell, 1952 (Box 2)
    - McCann Erickson, Inc., 1951-1954, (4 folders) (Box 2)
    - Newell-Emmett, 1948-1949, (2 folders) (Box 2)
    - William Esty Company, Inc., 1950 (Box 2)
    - Young & Rubicam, 1948-1954, (7 folders) (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous, 1948-1952, (5 folders) (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous, 1953-1954, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Aircraft
    - Boeing, 1949-1953, (5 folders) (Box 3)
    - Cessna, 1949-1953, (3 folders) (Box 3)
    - Consolidated Vultee, 1951-1953 (Box 3)
    - Douglas, 1949-1952, (3 folders) (Box 3)
    - Goodyear, 1949 (Box 3)
    - Grumman, 1949-1953, (5 folders) (Box 3)
    - Martin, 1949-1951, (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - North American Aviation, 1952-1953, (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - Northrop, 1953 (Box 3)
    - Piper Cub, 1953 (Box 3)
    - Republic Aviation, 1952-1953, (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - United Aircraft, 1949-1954, (6 folders) (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous, 1949-1953, (4 folders) (Box 3)
    - Curtiss-Wright, 1949-1954, (4 folders) (Box 3)
  - Banks and Banking
    - Credit and Finance Companies--Miscellaneous, 1955 (Box 3)
  - Electrical goods
    - Westinghouse, 1947 (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1950 (Box 4)
    - Wire Cable, 1946-1947, (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1953 (Box 4)
  - Fabrics and textile proceses
    - Miscellaneous, 1947 (Box 4)
    - Rayon--Miscellaneous, 1947-1952, (4 folders) (Box 4)
    - Silk, 1947-1954, (9 folders) (Box 4)
    - Wrinkle Resistant Processes, 1950-1951, (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - "Tebalized" crease resistant, 1947-1949, (3 folders) (Box 4)
    - Wool
      - Botany Mills, 1951-1953, (3 folders) (Box 4)
      - Botany Mills, 1948-1950, (3 folders) (Box 5)
      - Forstmann, 1947-1953, (7 folders) (Box 5)
      - Pacific Mills, 1948-1953, (4 folders) (Box 5)
    - Water Repellants--Zelan, 1953
      - Miscellaneous, 1949-1954, (5 folders) (Box 5)
      - Miscellaneous, 1950 (Box 6)
    - Water Repellants
      - Zelan, 1946-1951, (6 folders) (Box 6)
      - Miscellaneous, 1947-1953, (5 folders) (Box 6)
    - Wrinkle Resistant Processes--Tebalized, Unidure, etc., 1953-1954, (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - Fabrics and Textile Processes--Miscellaneous, 1954 (Box 6)
    - Rayon--Miscellaneous, 1948-1949, (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - Rayon--Burlington Mills Corp., 1948-1949, (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - Wool--Miscellaneous, 1948-1951, (2 folders) (Box 7)
    - Fabrics--Miscellaneous, 1948-1953, (6 folders) (Box 7)
  - Film--Miscellaneous, 1947 (Box 7)
  - Fire Protection Devices--Sprinklers, etc., 1946-1953, (8 folders) (Box 7)
  - Fireworks, 1951-1953, (3 folders) (Box 7)
  - Food and Kindred Products
    - Animal food
      - Miscellaneous, 1943-1953, (8 folders) (Box 7)
      - Miscellaneous, 1954 (Box 8)
      - Dash (Armour), 1948-1954, (7 folders) (Box 8)
      - Friskies, 1947-1953, (7 folders) (Box 8)
      - Gaines, 1947-1954, (8 folders) (Box 8)
      - Gro-Pup, 1947-1953, (7 folders) (Box 8)
      - Hunt Club, 1952 (Box 8)
      - Ideal (Wilson), 1948-1953, (6 folders) (Box 8)
      - Ken-L-Ration, 1947-1953, (7 folders) (Box 8)
      - Milkbone, 1951-1953, (3 folders) (Box 8)
      - Milkbone, 1943-1950, (7 folders) (Box 9)
      - Purina, 1948-1949, (2 folders) (Box 9)
      - Puss'N Boots, 1951-1953, (3 folders) (Box 9)
      - Red Heart, 1947-1953, (6 folders) (Box 9)
      - SAS, 1943 (Box 9)
      - Sergeant's, 1951-1953, (3 folders) (Box 9)
      - Miscellaneous, 1945-1951, (4 folders) (Box 9)
    - Baby Food
      - Beech-Nut, 1944-1954, (11 folders) (Box 9)
      - Clapp, 1944-1953, (10 folders) (Box 9)
      - Gerbers, 1952-1954, (3 folders) (Box 9)
  - Medicines--Merck, 1932-1934 (Box 9)
  - Greeting Cards
    - Norcross, 1946-1951, (4 folders) (Box 10)
    - Miscellaneous, 1947-1954, (6 folders) (Box 10)
  - Gasoline, Oils, and Lubricants
    - Union Oil Company of California, 1945-1954, (9 folders) (Box 10)
    - Tydol, 1940 (Box 10)
    - Veedol, 1941 (Box 10)
    - Miscellaneous, 1945-1954, (9 folders) (Box 10)
  - Games and Playing Cards, 1940-1954, (15 folders) (Box 11)
  - Garden Accessories, Tools, Etc., 1944-1954, (11 folders)
    - Farming and Gardening
      - Miscellaneous, 1940-1941, (2 folders) (Box 11)
      - Burpee, 1940-1941 (Box 11)
      - Davey, 1940-1941 (Box 11)
      - Ferry's, 1940 (Box 11)
      - Kellogg, 1941 (Box 11)
      - Vigoro, 1941 (Box 11)
  - Gift Services, 1952-1954, (3 folders) (Box 11)
  - Glass--Industrial, 1944-1953, (9 folders) (Box 11)
  - Household goods
    - Glass other than Cooking, 1947-1954, (1-7 of 9 folders) (Box 11)
    - Glass other than Cooking, 1947-1954, (8-9 of 9 folders) (Box 12)
    - Glass--Cooking, 1947-1954, (7 folders) (Box 12)
  - Hardware, Locks, Etc., 1942-1954, (11 folders) (Box 12)
  - Health Appliances, Lamps, Etc., 1945-1951, (7 folders) (Box 12)
  - Hearing Devices (hearing aids), 1947-1954, (8 folders) (Box 12)
  - Sewing Machines, 1945 (Box 12)
  - Heating Devices
    - Oil, 1946-1954, (8 folders) (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous, 1953-1954, (2 folders) (Box 12)
    - Coal, 1947-1953, (7 folders) (Box 13)
    - Electric, 1947-1954, (8 folders) (Box 13)
    - Fireplaces, 1947-1953, (6 folders) (Box 13)
    - Gas, 1947-1954, (8 folders) (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous, 1947-1952, (6 folders) (Box 13)
  - Hospitals, 1948-1949, (2 folders) (Box 13)
  - Hotels and Restaurants, 1952-1954, (3 folders) (Box 13)
  - Hotels and Restaurants, 1947-1951, (5 folders) (Box 14)
  - Household Goods
    - Kitchen Equipment
      - Miscellaneous, 1947-1954, (7 folders) (Box 14)
      - Youngstown Kitchens, 1950 (Box 14)
    - Mending Aids (Tape, etc.), 1945-1953, (10 folders) (Box 14)
    - Name Tape, 1945-1953, (5 folders) (Box 14)
    - Notions, 1949-1953, (5 folders) (Box 14)
    - Notions, zippers, etc., 1945-1948, (3 folders) (Box 15)
    - Odor Dispellents
      - Air Wick, 1943-1954, (10 folders) (Box 15)
      - Miscellaneous, 1947-1954, (7 folders) (Box 15)
    - Polishes
      - Floor (including mops), 1947-1954, (8 folders) (Box 15)
      - Furniture, 1947-1954, (9 folders) (Box 15)
      - Miscellaneous, 1946-1954, (8 folders) (Box 16)
      - Silver/metal, 1943-1954, (11 folders) (Box 16)
      - Shoe, 1943-1954, (12 folders) (Box 16)
    - Household--Miscellaneous (including Peter Putter), 1945-1947, (3 folders) (Box 16)
  - Insecticides and Exterminators
    - Garden, 1952-1954, (4 folders) (Box 16)
    - Moth, 1946-1953, (5 folders) (Box 16)
    - Vermin (Flies, rats, etc.)
      - Bug-a-Boo, 1946 (Box 16)
      - Destro, 1946 (Box 16)
      - Miscellaneous, 1942-1953, (6 folders) (Box 16)
      - Aer-a-sol, 1946-1952, (4 folders) (Box 16)
      - Fly Ded, 1946-1950, (2 folders) (Box 16)
      - Agricultural, 1946 (Box 16)
      - Miscellaneous, 1946-1952, (3 folders) (Box 17)
      - Flit, 1945 (Box 17)
      - Garden, 1949-1950, (2 folders) (Box 17)
      - Miscellaneous, 1947-1949, (2 folders) (Box 17)
  - Institutional, 1949-1954, (6 folders) (Box 17)
  - Publications (Box 17)
  - Newspapers
    - Chicago Tribune, 1947-1954, (8 folders) (Box 18)
    - Hearst, 1947-1953, (7 folders) (Box 18)
    - Metropolitan Group, 1947-1954, (8 folders) (Box 18)
    - Minneapolis Star Journal and Tribune, 1947-1954, (8 folders) (Box 18)
    - Philadelphia Bulletin, 1947-1954, (8 folders) (Box 18)
    - New York World Telegram and the Sun, 1950 (Box 18)
    - Philadelphia Inquirer, 1946-1953, (8 folders) (Box 18)
    - Portland Journal, 1944-1953, (9 folders) (Box 18)
    - Portland Oregonian, 1941 (Box 18)
    - St. Louis Globe Democrat, 1941-1942, (2 folders) (Box 18)
    - Troy Record, 1942 (Box 18)
    - Washington Post, 1942 (Box 18)
    - Washington Spokesman-Review, 1942 (Box 18)
    - Williamsport Grit, 1942 (Box 18)
    - (NY) World Telegram, 1947-1954, (6 folders) (Box 19)
    - Miscellaneous, 1940-1954, (15 folders) (Box 19)
  - Propaganda, 1941 (Box 19)
  - Comics, 1941 (Box 20)
  - Magazines
    - Better Homes & Gardens, 1964 (Box 20)
    - Fortune, 1964 (Box 20)
    - Good Housekeeping, 1964 (Box 20)
    - Holiday, 1964 (Box 20)
    - Ladies' Home Journal, 1964 (Box 20)
    - Life, 1964 (Box 20)
    - Look, 1964 (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous, 1964 (Box 20)
    - Reader's Digest, 1964 (Box 20)
    - Time, 1964 (Box 21)
    - Woman's Day, 1964 (Box 21)
  - Public relations
    - Youngstown, 1964 (Box 21)
    - U.S. Steel Corp., 1964 (Box 21)
    - Annual Statements, 1943-1953, (11 folders) (Box 21)
    - Employer-Employee Relations, 1943-1950, (7 folders) (Box 21)
    - Government criticism, replies to, 1943-1952, (7 folders) (Box 21)
    - Inflation, 1946-1951, (3 folders) (Box 21)
    - Institutional Advertising, 1945-1946, (2 folders) (Box 21)
    - Private Enterprise, 1947-1953, (3 folders) (Box 21)
    - Strikes, 1943-1952, (5 folders) (Box 22)
    - Miscellaneous, 1944-1954, (9 folders) (Box 22)
    - Public Utilities--Miscellaneous, 1941-1947, (2 folders) (Box 22)
    - Annual Statements--Miscellaneous, 1948-1952, (3 folders) (Box 22)
  - Public utilities
    - Miscellaneous, 1944-1954, (10 folders) (Box 22)
    - Commonwealth and Southern Corp., 1940-1941, (2 folders) (Box 22)
  - Publishing companies
    - Miscellaneous, 1941-1954, (10 folders) (Box 23)
    - McGraw-Hill, 1941-1953, (13 folders) (Box 23)
    - Rand McNally, 1941-1942, (2 folders) (Box 23)
    - Curtis, 1942 (Box 23)
  - Real Estate, 1940-1953, (14 folders) (Box 23)
  - Brokers and Brokerage Houses, 1944-1949, (6 folders) (Box 23)
  - Reducing and Exercise, 1947-1954, (8 folders) (Box 23)
  - Refrigerants and Refrigeration, 1947-1952, (6 folders) (Box 24)
  - Squibb, 1952 (Box 24)
  - Parke, Davis, and Co., 1952 (Box 24)
  - Religious Advertising, 1945 (Box 24)
  - Rubber Goods and Synthetic Rubber
    - Goodrich (Koroseal), 1946 (Box 24)
    - Firestone, 1943 (Box 24)
  - Public Utilities, 1943 (Box 24)
  - Resorts, 1950-1954 (Box 24)
  - Restaurants, 1950-1954, (3 folders) (Box 24)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 24)
    - Automat, 1942 (Box 24)
    - Childs, 1940-1941, (2 folders) (Box 24)
  - Rope, 1946-1953, (8 folders) (Box 24)
  - Rubber Goods and Synthetic Rubber
    - Goodrich, 1953 (Box 24)
    - Du Pont, 1940 (Box 24)
    - Firestone, 1944-1954, (11 folders) (Box 24)
    - Goodrich, 1949-1954, (7 folders) (Box 24)
    - Goodrich (including Koroseal), 1940-1947 (Box 25)
    - Goodyear, 1946-1954, (9 folders) (Box 25)
    - Hewitt, 1942-1953, (11 folders) (Box 25)
    - Kleinerts, 1941 (Box 25)
    - Republic, 1942 (Box 25)
    - Seiberling, 1943-1944, (2 folders) (Box 25)
    - U.S. Rubber Co., 1949-1954, (7 folders) (Box 25)
    - Miscellaneous, 1947-1948, (2 folders) (Box 25)
    - Miscellaneous, 1944-1954, (8 folders) (Box 26)
    - U.S. Rubber Co., 1944-1948, (3 folders) (Box 26)
    - Seiberling, 1948 (Box 26)
  - Rust Preventatives, 1943-1953, (10 folders) (Box 26)
  - Safes, 1942 (Box 26)
  - Scales, 1945-1954, (8 folders) (Box 26)
  - Schools
    - Dancing, 1950, 1954, (2 folders) (Box 26)
    - Correspondence schools, 1950-1953, (4 folders) (Box 26)
    - Arthur Murray, 1947-1957, (7 folders) (Box 26)
    - Correspondence schools
      - International, 1940-1942, (3 folders) (Box 26)
      - La Salle, 1940-1942, (3 folders) (Box 26)
      - Miscellaneous, 1940-1947, (7 folders) (Box 26)
    - Language, 1941-1947, (5 folders) (Box 27)
      - Berlitz, 1942-1943, (2 folders) (Box 27)
    - Miscellaneous, 1943-1953, (9 folders) (Box 27)
    - Careers--Miscellaneous, 1942 (Box 27)
    - Dancing
      - Dale Studios, 1947-1948, (2 folders) (Box 27)
      - Don Pallini, 1947-1948, (2 folders) (Box 27)
      - Maya Boleyn, 1947 (Box 27)
      - Miscellaneous, 1946-1949, (4 folders) (Box 27)
    - Art
      - Federal, 1941 (Box 27)
    - Business
      - Ballard, 1941 (Box 27)
    - Correspondence schools
      - Dale Carnegie, 1941 (Box 27)
  - Seeds, Plants, and Fertilizers
    - Miscellaneous, 1945-1953, (10 folders) (Box 27)
    - Burpee, 1942-1943, (2 folders) (Box 27)
    - P. Henderson, 1942 (Box 27)
    - Loma, 1942 (Box 27)
  - Selling
    - House to house, 1949-1953, (3 folders) (Box 27)
    - Direct, 1950-1952, (2 folders) (Box 27)
  - Ships and Shipbuilding Equipment except Engines--Miscellaneous, 1944-1950, (5 folders) (Box 27)
  - Soap and scouring compounds
    - Oakite, 1941 (Box 27)
    - Old Dutch Cleanser, 1941-1946, (6 folders) (Box 27)
    - Old Dutch Cleanser, 1922-1940, (14 folders) (Box 28)
    - Merlin, 1929 (Box 28)
    - Oakite, 1944 (Box 28)
    - Old Dutch Cleanser, 1935-1936, (2 folders) (Box 29)
    - Oakite, 1927-1939, (4 folders) (Box 29)
    - Pronto, 1930 (Box 29)
    - Sani-Flush, 1931-1942, (7 folders) (Box 29)
    - Chore Girl, 1931 (Box 29)
    - Sapolio, 1927-1939, (3 folders) (Box 29)
    - Silver Dust, 1933-1937, (4 folders) (Box 29)
    - Sunbrite, 1936-1944, (7 folders) (Box 29)
    - Sun-Ray, 1934 (Box 29)
    - Vano, 1941 (Box 29)
    - Volite, 1930 (Box 29)
    - Wear-Ever, 1944-1945 (Box 29)
    - Wyandotte, 1930-1937, (3 folders) (Box 29)
    - Wet Me Wet, 1934 (Box 29)
    - Tuffy, 1954 (Box 29)
    - S.O.S., 1942-1948, (5 folders) (Box 29)
    - S.O.S., 1924-1953, (16 folders) (Box 30)
    - Miscellaneous, 1928-1944, (10 folders) (Box 30)
    - Soaps--Institutional
      - Procter & Gamble, 1950 (Box 30)
      - Miscellaneous, 1950 (Box 30)
  - Soap and scouring compounds
    - Miscellaneous, 1947-1953, (5 folders) (Box 30)
    - Miscellaneous, 1950-1954, (2 folders) (Box 31)
    - Borax, 1927-1933, (2 folders) (Box 31)
  - Softeners, Water, 1943-1954, (12 folders) (Box 31)
  - Sponges, 1950-1953, (4 folders) (Box 31)
  - Sports and Sporting Goods, 1941-1954, (15 folders) (Box 31)
  - Spray Systems--See also Fire Protection Devices, 1946 (Box 31)
  - Stores--Bakery--Hanscom, 1942 (Box 31)
  - Store advertising
    - Chain drug, 1951-1952, (2 folders) (Box 31)
    - Chain drug, 1948-1949, (2 folders) (Box 32)
    - Chain grocery, 1947-1952, (5 folders) (Box 32)
    - Chain variety, 1947-1954, (5 folders) (Box 32)
    - Chain miscellaneous, 1947-1952, (2 folders) (Box 32)
    - Department stores
      - Altman's, 1947-1953, (5 folders) (Box 32)
      - Best & Co., 1952 (Box 32)
      - Bloomingdale's, 1947-1953, (4 folders) (Box 32)
      - Miscellaneous, 1950, (2 folders) (Box 32)
      - Lord & Taylor, 1947-1953, (7 folders) (Box 32)
      - Macy's, 1947-1953, (7 folders) (Box 32)
      - Best & Co., 1950 (Box 32)
      - Saks Fifth Avenue, 1950 (Box 32)
      - John Wanamaker, 1947-1953, (5 folders) (Box 32)
    - Bakeries, 1954 (Box 33)
    - Chain drug, 1950-1954, (3 folders) (Box 33)
  - Testimonial Advertising, 1950/1953 (Box 33)
  - "Tie-in" Advertisements, 1953 (Box 33)
  - Warehouses, 1950-1952, (2 folders) (Box 33)
  - Water Treatment Systems, 1949-1952, (3 folders) (Box 33)
  - Wax, 1949 (Box 33)
  - Welfare and Religious Organizations--Red Cross and other, 1948-1953, (8 folders) (Box 33)
  - Yarns and fibers
    - Celanese, 1944-1953, (9 folders) (Box 33)
    - Lastex (United States Rubber Co.), 1948-1952, (5 folders) (Box 33)
    - Miscellaneous, 1948-1953, (6 folders) (Box 33)
  - Beverages
    - A-Treat, 1945-1946 (Box 33)
    - Blatz, 1943 (Box 33)
    - Boller Ginger Ale, 1943-1945 (Box 33)
    - Canada Dry, 1931 (Box 33)
    - Beverages--Mineral Water--Canada Dry, 1935-1938 (Box 33)
    - Canada Dry, 1943 (Box 33)
    - Canada Dry, 1944-1954, (11 folders) (Box 34)
    - Coca-Cola, 1922-1923 (Box 34)
    - Clicquot Club, 1924-1925, (2 folders) (Box 34)
    - Clicquot Club, 1926-1952, (18 folders) (Box 35)
    - Cott, 1953-1954 (Box 35)
    - Cotton Club, 1943 (Box 35)
    - Coca-Cola, 1920-1936, (11 folders) (Box 36)
    - Coca-Cola, 1937-1945, (9 folders) (Box 37)
    - Coca-Cola, 1944-1954, (11 folders) (Box 38)
    - Dr. Pepper, 1943-1953, (2 folders) (Box 39)
    - Evervess, 1946-1949, (3 folders) (Box 39)
    - Grapette, 1940s-1950s (Box 39)
    - Hires, 1919-1953, (13 folders) (Box 39)
    - Hoffman, 1928-1931, (6 folders) (Box 39)
    - Hoffman, 1932-1954, (20 folders) (Box 40)
    - Kool Aid, 1943-1952 (Box 40)
    - Mavis, 1943/1945/1947 (Box 40)
    - Mission Dry Sparkling, 1929-1930 (Box 40)
    - Moxie, 1925-1945, (6 folders) (Box 40)
    - Myer 1890, 1947-1951 (Box 40)
    - No-Cal, 1952-1954 (Box 40)
    - Store Advertising--Specialty--Miscellaneous, 1952 (Box 40)
    - Store Advertising--Retail--Chain--Grocery, 1954 (Box 40)
  - Beverages
    - O'Keefe's, 1921-1929, (3 folders) (Box 41)
    - Old Colony, 1947/1949/1953 (Box 41)
    - Old Union, 1928 (Box 41)
    - Orange Crush, 1920-1932, 1940s, (2 folders) (Box 41)
    - Pale Moon, 1928-1929 (Box 41)
    - Par-T-Pak, 1950, 1953-1954 (Box 41)
    - Pepsi Cola, 1936-1945, (8 folders) (Box 41)
    - Pepsi Cola, 1946-1954, (9 folders) (Box 42)
    - Phillips, 1944 (Box 42)
    - Quinac Canada Dry, 1953-1954 (Box 42)
    - Royal Crown Cola (RC Cola), 1942-1954, (13 folders) (Box 42)
    - Schweppes, 1941-1954, (2 folders) (Box 42)
    - Seely's, 1929-1930, (2 folders) (Box 42)
    - Seely's, 1931-1934, (3 folders) (Box 43)
    - Seven-Up (7-Up), 1944-1954, (4 folders) (Box 43)
    - Silver King, 1925 (Box 43)
    - Simpson Spring, 1929 and previous (Box 43)
    - Sno-Cola, 1942 (Box 43)
    - Spur, 1941-1954, (4 folders) (Box 43)
    - Squirt, 1944-45, 1949-54 (Box 43)
    - Suburban Club, 1943 (Box 43)
    - TIP, 1945-1947 (Box 43)
    - Tom Collins, 1932 (Box 43)
    - White Rock, 1929 and previous-1953, (4 folders) (Box 43)
    - Zep, 1943 (Box 43)
    - Soft drinks miscellaneous, 1927-1954, (5 folders) (Box 43)
    - Cola drinks, 1943-1954, (7 folders) (Box 43)
    - Fruit flavor drinks, 1920s-1950s, (3 folders) (Box 43)
    - Ginger ale, 1920-1941, (8 folders) (Box 44)
    - Root beer, 1918-1954, (12 folders) (Box 44)
    - Mineral water
      - Appolinaris, 1924-1929, (2 folders) (Box 44)
      - Aquazone, 1924-25, 1927-28 (Box 44)
      - Arrowhead, 1930-1932, (2 folders) (Box 44)
      - Celestins Vichy, 1921-25/1938/1947 (Box 44)
      - Corinnis, 1928-1930 (Box 44)
      - Gerolsteiner, 1928-1931 (Box 44)
      - Londonderry, 1920s (Box 44)
      - Manitoo, 1918 (Box 44)
      - Mountain Valley Mineral Water, 1917-1947 (Box 44)
      - Perrier, 1917/1953 (Box 44)
      - Pluto Water, 1925-1927 (Box 44)
      - Poland Water, 1925, 1940-1946 (Box 44)
      - Puritas, 1929 (Box 44)
      - Saratoga, 1925-1946 (Box 44)
      - Shasta, 1928-1929 (Box 44)
      - Sleepy Water, 1929-1931 (Box 44)
      - Sparkletts, 1931 (Box 44)
      - Miscellaneous, 1917-1936, (8 folders) (Box 44)
      - Miscellaneous, 1937-1953, (8 folders) (Box 45)
    - Fruit and fruit flavor drinks, 1920s-1951, (7 folders)
      - Cider (primarily Wayne County brand), 1927-1929 (Box 45)
      - Orange drinks, 1930-1940, (3 folders) (Box 45)
      - Nedick's, 1920s (Box 45)
      - Squeeze, 1920s (Box 45)
      - Kool-Aid, 1941-1953, (4 folders) (Box 45)
      - Lemade, 1927 (Box 45)
      - Lemon drinks, 1930 (Box 45)
      - Nesbitt's, 1941-1950, (2 folders) (Box 45)
      - Sumoro, 1927 (Box 45)
      - Orange/grapefruit drinks, 1928 (Box 45)
      - Vegetable drinks, 1930s-1950s (Box 45)
    - Chocolate beverages and cocoa
      - Baker's, 1926-1941, (9 folders) (Box 45)
      - Mavis, 1928-1929, (2 folders) (Box 45)
      - Miscellaneous, 1943-1953, (10 folders) (Box 46)
      - Ghirardelli's, 1910s-1933, (2 folders) (Box 46)
      - Nestle's, 1940-1942, (3 folders) (Box 46)
      - Mavis, 1929 (Box 46)
      - Baker's, 1921-1931, (6 folders) (Box 46)
      - Bensdorp's, 1912-1932, (3 folders) (Box 46)
      - Bunte, 1919-1920 (Box 46)
      - Fry's, 1936-1937 (Box 46)
      - Cowan's, 1910s-1920s (Box 46)
      - Hyler's, 1910s-1920s (Box 46)
      - Lipton's, 1922 (Box 46)
      - Lowney's, 1913-1918 (Box 46)
      - Maillard's, 1910s-1920 (Box 46)
      - Miscellaneous, 1954 (Box 46)
    - Beverages--Cider--Wayne County, 1931 (Box 46)
    - Beverages--Dietene, 1936 (Box 46)
    - Beverages--Department Stores (primarily wines and liquors solde at department stores), 1936 (Box 46)
    - Wines and Liquors
      - Ancient Age, 1942-1952, (3 folders) (Box 46)
      - Bacardi, 1936-1954, (6 folders) (Box 46)
      - Bellows Gin, 1945-1948, (3 folders) (Box 46)
      - Bell's, 1947-1954, (3 folders) (Box 46)
      - Benedictine, 1944-1954, (3 folders) (Box 46)
      - Booth's, 1942-1954, (3 folders) (Box 47)
      - Brugal Rum, 1944-1947, (3 folders) (Box 47)
      - Canada Dry Gin, 1933-1936, (2 folders) (Box 47)
      - Carstairs, 1936-1953, (15 folders) (Box 47)
      - Cherry Heering, 1946-1954, (3 folders) (Box 47)
      - Corby's, 1943 (Box 47)
      - Corby's Reserve, 1944-1950, (7 folders) (Box 47)
      - Corby's Reserve, 1951-1954, (3 folders) (Box 48)
      - Coronet Brandy, 1942-1954, (5 folders) (Box 48)